In 1959 a lot of people were killing time. Kit and Holly were killing people.
Badlands is a crime, drama, romance film directed by Terrence Malick.
An impressionable teenage girl from a dead-end town and her older greaser
boyfriend embark on a killing spree in the South Dakota badlands.
Kit Carruthers, played by Martin Sheen.
Holly Sargis, played by Sissy Spacek.
Holly's Father, played by Warren Oates.
Cato, played by Ramon Bieri.
Deputy, played by Alan Vint.
Sheriff, played by Gary Littlejohn.
Badlands is a 1973 American neo-noir period crime drama film written,
produced and directed by Terrence Malick, in his directorial debut.
The film stars Martin Sheen and Sissy Spacek, and follows Holly Sargis (Spacek), a 15-year
old who goes on a killing spree with her partner, Kit Carruthers (Sheen).
The film also stars Warren Oates and Ramon Bieri.
While the story is fictional, it is loosely based on the real-life murder spree of
Charles Starkweather and his girlfriend, Caril Ann Fugate, in 1958.
Badlands was released in 1973 to positive reviews from critics, who particularly praised its
cinematography, soundtrack—which includes pieces by Carl Orff—and the lead performances.
At the 28th British Academy Film Awards, Spacek was nominated for the Most Promising Newcomer to Leading Film
Roles award, and Sheen won the Best Actor award at the San Sebastián International Film Festival.
In 1993, the film was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the
Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
The film explores themes of mass murder, based on true
story, fugitive, on the run, on the road.
The tone is emotional.